<profile xmlns="http://ainq.com/ig-definition" id="SANER" chapter='1' codingsystems="SanerBedType" valuesets="BedLocationOperationalStatus BedProperty BedType">
	<domain id="AI">
	    <org>Audaciuo
	     s Inquiry</org>
	    <name>Situational Awareness for Novel Epidemic Response</name>
	    <description></description>
	    <overview file="SANER-overview.md"/>
	</domain>
    <name>Situational Awareness for Novel Epidemic Response</name>
    <description>The Situational Awareness for Novel Epidemic Response Implementation Guide enables transmission
of high level situational awareness information from inpatient facilities to centralized data repositories
to support the treatment of novel influenza-like illness.
    </description>
    <!-- overview is optional -->
    <overview file="SANER-overview.md"/>
    <!-- option is optional and repeatable -->
    <option id="Push">
	    <name>Push Option</name>
	    <description>An actor implementing the Push Option supports the periodic push of a Bundle of records
describing the current status of health delivery resources to a centralized collection point.
	    </description>
	    <overview/>
	    <participant actor='AvailabilitySource'>
	       <description>An Availability Source implementing the Push Option periodically sends updates to the
Availability Collector using the [Update Availability](transaction-2.html) transaction.
</description>
	    </participant>
    </option>
    <option id="Pull">
        <name>Pull Option</name>
        <description>An actor implementing the Pull Option supports use of the [Query Availability] transaction made from
an Availability Collector to enable reporting of the current status of selected health delivery resources .</description>
        <overview/>
        <participant actor='AvailabilitySource'>
           <description>An Availability Source implementing the Pull Option periodically is periodically queried by an
Availability Collector using the [Query Availability](transaction-1.html) transaction to enable collection of the current status.
</description>
        </participant>
    </option>
    <option id="Resource">
        <name>Resource Option</name>
        <description>An actor supporting the Resource Option can describe the status of non-bed treatment
resources, such as ventilators, respirators, infusion pumps, monitoring equipment, et cetera</description>
        <overview/>
        <participant actor='AvailabilitySource'>
            <description>An Availability Source implementing the Resource Option can send updates on other Resources
(e.g., ventilators, respirators, other medical equipment).</description>
        </participant>
        <participant actor='AvailabilityCollector'>
            <description>An Availability Collector implementing the Resource Option can request updates on other Resources
(e.g., ventilators, respirators, other medical equipment), or aggregate data updates provided about these
resources.</description>
        </participant>
        <participant actor='AvailabilityReporter'>
            <description>An Availability Reporter implementing the Resource Option can reports data about other Resources
(e.g., ventilators, respirators, other medical equipment).</description>
        </participant>
    </option>
    <!-- standard is repeatable -->
    <standard id="FHIR-R4">
        <name>HL7 FHIR Release 4.0</name>
        <url>http://www.hl7.org/FHIR/R4</url>
    </standard>
    <standard id="RFC-7230">
        <url>https://ietf.org/rfc/rfc7230.html</url>
        <name>Hypertext Transfer Protocol - HTTP/1.1</name>
    </standard>
    <standard id="RFC-7540">
        <url>https://ietf.org/rfc/rfc7540.html</url>
        <name>Hypertext Transfer Protocol - HTTP/2</name>
    </standard>
    <standard id="RFC-3986">
        <url>https://ietf.org/rfc/rfc3986.html</url>
        <name>Uniform Resource Identifier (URI): Generic Syntax</name>
    </standard>
    <standard id="RFC-4627">
        <url>https://ietf.org/rfc/rfc4627.html</url>
        <name>The application/json Media Type for JavaScript Object Notation (JSON)</name>
    </standard>
    <standard id="RFC-6585">
        <url>https://ietf.org/rfc/rfc6585.html</url>
        <name>Additional HTTP Status Codes</name>
    </standard>

    <!-- usecase is optional and repeatable -->
    <usecase id="BED" actors="AvailabilitySource AvailabilityCollector" transactions="PULL-TX PUSH-TX" content="bed-group bed-location">
	    <name>Collecting Bed Availability</name>
        <description>This use case addresses the exchange of data from Facilities to a Centralized
reporting system for Public Health</description>
	    <!-- overview is optional -->
	    <overview>Overview TBD</overview>
	    <step id="BED-STEP1" from="AvailabilityCollector" to="AvailabilitySource" returns="now">
            <name>Availability Collector Initiates Search</name>
            <description>The Availability Collector identifies features associated with a group of
bed resources that it wishes to collect data about.  For example, the Availability Collector can
request information about ICU, med/surg, or ED beds available or in use.</description>
            <overview>TBD</overview>
	        <return id="BED-STEP2" from="AvailabilitySource" to="AvailabilityCollector" returns="now">
	            <name>Availability Source Reports Aggregate Data</name>
	            <description>The Availability Source reports aggregate data about a group of beds based
	                on specified bed characteristics</description>
	            <overview>TBD</overview>
	        </return>
	    </step>
    </usecase>
    <usecase id="Reporting" actors="AvailabilityCollector AvailabilityReporter" transactions="REPORT-TX" content="bed-group bed-location">
        <name>Reporting on Bed Availability</name>
        <description>TBD</description>
        <!-- overview is optional -->
        <overview>TBD</overview>
        <step id="Reporting-STEP1" from="Public Health User" to="AvailabilityReporter" returns="now">
            <name>User Initiates Search</name>
            <description>The Public Health User navigates to a web page where collected data is reported.</description>
            <overview>TBD</overview>
            <step id="Aggregating-STEP2" from="AvailabilityReporter" to="AvailabilityCollector" returns="now">
                <name>Availability Reporter gathers data from Availability Collectors</name>
                <description>The Availability Reporter gathers and aggregates data from one or more Availability Collectors.</description>
                <overview>The means by which gathering and aggregation is performed is not further specified
by this implementation guide. However, the Availability Reporter can obtain data from an Availability Collector by using other transactions
within this profile if desired.</overview>
            </step>
            <return>
                <name>Display Results</name>
                <description>The Availability Reporter displays an overview of aggregated regional results to the
user, and additional links which enable navigation to finer grained or alternative displays.</description>
                <overview>Data can be displayed as aggregated or fine-grained status information based
on the current focus of the public health user.  It may be shown as a map, a table, or a graph.</overview>
            </return>
        </step>
        <step id="Reporting-STEP2" from="Public Health User" to="AvailabilityReporter" returns="now">
            <name>User refines Focus or Form of Display</name>
            <description>The Public Health User selects a new form of display (e.g., Map, table or graph) or refines their
focus (e.g., wider or smaller region).</description>
            <overview>TBD</overview>
            <return>
                <name>Display Refined Results</name>
                <description>The Availability Collector modifies the users focus and reporting format</description>
                <overview>TBD</overview>
            </return>
        </step>
    </usecase>
    <!--  Other Use Cases can describe options -->
    <actor id="AvailabilitySource">
        <name>Availability Source</name>
        <description>The Availability Source Actor reports results for a single facility, collection of facilities
        or aggragated data for a region</description>
        <!-- overview is optional -->
        <overview>TBD</overview>
        <supports-tx transaction="PULL-TX" as="server">
            <role>Responds to a query, reporting on selected data.</role>
            <on-condition>
                <description>When the Availability Source supports the Pull Option</description>
            </on-condition>
        </supports-tx>
        <supports-tx transaction="PUSH-TX" as="client">
            <role>Periodically pushes selected data to an Availability Collector.</role>
            <on-condition>
                <description>When the Availability Source supports the Push Option</description>
            </on-condition>
        </supports-tx>
        <!-- requirement is optional and can repeat -->
        <requires id="COLLECT-R1">
            <description>An Availability Source **shall** implement at least one of the following options:
* Push Option
* Pull Option
            </description>
            <overview>
</overview>
        </requires>
    </actor>
    <actor id="AvailabilityCollector">
        <name>Availability Collector</name>
        <description>The Availability Collector gathers data on resource availablity from other systems</description>
        <requires-tx transaction="PULL-TX" as="client">
            <role>Collects availability data on a periodic basis</role>
        </requires-tx>
        <requires-tx transaction="PUSH-TX" as="server">
            <role>Receives availability data on a periodic basis</role>
        </requires-tx>
    </actor>

    <actor id="AvailabilityReporter">
        <name>Availability Reporter</name>
        <description>The Availability Reporter allows users to view reports on aggregated and fine-grained
data gathered from multiple Availability Sources.
        </description>
        <requires-tx transaction="REPORT-TX" as="self">
            <role>Display reports using availability data</role>
        </requires-tx>
    </actor>

    <transaction id="PULL-TX" standards="FHIR-R4 RFC-7230">
        <name>Query Availability</name>
        <description>The Query Availability transaction allows an Availability Collector to
periodically query about the availability of a resource from an Availability Source.</description>
        <!-- like steps, messages can nest to support activation lines -->
        <message from="AvailabilityCollector" to="AvailabilitySource">
            <name>Search Group Request</name>
            <description></description>
            <trigger id="TRIGGER1">
                <name>Periodic Reporting Interval Elapsed</name>
            </trigger>
            <semantics>
                <description>The Availability sends a query using an HTTP GET or POST transaction
to the Group endpoint of the Availability Source requesting information on available resources.</description>
                <overview>The GET Query uses the FHIR [Search](https://hl7.org/fhir/R4/search.html) syntax to
query for information about one or more groups. The query parameters ...</overview>
            </semantics>
            <action by="AvailabilityCollector">
                <name>An Availability Collector sends a Query to the Availability Source</name>
                <description>The Availability Collector sends a query.</description>
                <overview></overview>
            </action>
            <result>
                <name>Search Group Response</name>
                <description>This transaction enables query on the availability of resources.</description>
                <trigger id="TRIGGER-1a">
                   <name>A query of Group resources has been requested.</name>
                </trigger>
                <semantics>
                    <description>The Availability Source responds with a Bundle of Groups matching the query parameters.</description>
                    <overview>The groups in the resource will conform to the profiles for the
Bed Availability Group or Device Availability Group described eslewhere in this Implementation Guide</overview>
                </semantics>
                <action by="AvailabilitySource">
                    <name>Availability Source responds with Bundle</name>
                    <description>The Availability Source will generate a Bundle of matching Group resources and return it with a 200 OK response.</description>
                    <overview>If there are no matching resources, the Availability Source responds with an empty bundle and a 200 OK response.
If errors occur during retrieval, the Availability Source makes a best effort to return what it can and may include an OperationOutcome resource
in the response indicating more details about what might be missing.  If the retrieval cannot be performed, the Availability Source may return
a 4XX error or 5XX error to indicate that an error has occured.
                    </overview>
                </action>
            </result>
        </message>
    </transaction>

    <transaction id="PUSH-TX" standards="FHIR-R4 RFC-7230">
        <name>Update Availability</name>
        <description>The Update Availability transaction allows an Availability Source to
periodically update the availability of resources to an Availability Collector.</description>
        <message from="AvailabilitySource" to="AvailabilityCollector">
            <name>Push Availability Bundle</name>
            <description></description>
            <trigger id="TRIGGER2">
                <name>Periodic Reporting Interval elapsed</name>
                <description>brief description (markdown)</description>
                <overview>more detailed description (markdown)</overview>
            </trigger>
            <action by="AvailabilitySource">
                <name>Availability Source reports a Bundle</name>
                <description>The Availability Source posts a Bundle of matching Group resources to the Availability Collector.</description>
                <overview>If there are no matching resources, the Availability Source reports with an empty bundle. If errors occur during
producing the report, the Availability Source makes a best effort to send what it
can and may include an OperationOutcome resource in the bundle indicating more
details about what might be missing.
                </overview>
            </action>
            <action by="AvailabilityCollector">
                <name>The Availability Collector responds with Success</name>
                <description>The Availability Collector reports success using 200 OK, 201 Created, or 204 No Content to indicate a successful update.</description>
                <overview>If an error occured during the update, the Availability collector should report it using a 4XX or 5XX error depending on the cause.</overview>
            </action>
        </message>
    </transaction>
    <transaction id="REPORT-TX" standards="RFC-7230">
        <name>Report Results</name>
        <description>The Report Results transaction allows users (e.g., Public Health Officials) to view current resource availability.</description>
        <message from="AvailabilityReporter" to="AvailabilityReporter">
            <name>Report Availability</name>
            <description></description>
        </message>
    </transaction>
    <content id="bed-group">
        <name>Bed Availability Group</name>
        <description>This content profile describes the structure of a Group in a Bundle describing Bed Availability</description>
        <overview></overview>
    </content>
    <content id="device-group">
        <name>Device Availability Group</name>
        <description>This content profile describes the structure of a Group in a Bundle describing Device Availability</description>
        <overview></overview>
    </content>
    <content id="bed-location">
        <name>Single Bed Availability Status</name>
        <description>This content profile describes the structure of a Location Resource providing features of a supporting-device in a Bed Availability Group</description>
        <overview></overview>
    </content>
    <content id="supporting-device">
        <name>Single Device Availability Status</name>
        <description>This content profile describes the structure of a Device Resource providing features for a Device in a Device Availability Group</description>
        <overview></overview>
    </content>
        <content id="resource-location">
        <name>Resource Location</name>
        <description>This content profile describes the structure of a Location Resource describing the physical location (e.g., building)
where a bed or device is located</description>
        <overview></overview>
    </content>
</profile>
